All right, everyone. Next, we talk about scoop and that is about excess as well.
You can refer to that as either scope or excess. Remember, we talked about encapsulation
and the ability to disclose or to hide details from the end user from someone else, right?
And we took real-world analogy about understanding encapsulation as well. If you want to recollect,
just go back to that video and then come back to this one, but that is about encapsulation.
So how do we do it in Java? We do that with the concept of excess specifiers, right?
And that is how you would be able to open up your code to whomever you wish, right? That is
Java gives you complete control as a developer, right? So starting with, as I said,
we'll do that with scope. And for that, we have four types, four levels of scope in Java,
out of which only three are keywords, right? And starting with, I'll say package private,
right? Or some refer to it as package only, but I prefer this wording as more appropriate,
right? I'll tell you why shortly, but package private is the default scope in Java and it's not
a keyword, right? Because it's the default scope. If you do not put scope of members in Java,
that means it has a default scope. And now you know, what is that? That is package private.
So the next one we have is the referred to that as public, right? Which is a keyword,
then we have protected. And then we have private. All right. So four levels of scope in Java,
out of which only three are keywords that is public, protected or private. And package private
is the default scope. It is not a keyword as a tool. You just remember that. And maybe you
apply scope. It's very important for you to understand that first. So scope is applicable in Java
two levels. So either at the class level, right? Or later on, you will see at the interface
level as well. But because for now, we're just dealing with classes. So just think about it as
be applicable either at the class level or at the member level. Now wait a minute, what are members now,
right? I didn't talk about them, but we have covered them. So members of a class are it's
instance variables and methods. And I'm going to refrace with you for clarity. Instance variables
and methods of a class are referred to as members of class, right? Collectivity. And at the member
level, you can put in the scope or at the class level. That is where scope is resolved in Java. And
we just have a look at it. And both those, those approaches are just right now. So let's go in
two R I D E. But remember, we just have these four levels of scope in Java, right? And what I'll do
is I'll just head over back to my ID. And that is intelligent again. And let's go on and quickly create
a new class this time. And I'll just call it scope work. So I'll maximize this,
have the main method again. So, but now before taking on scope, we need to understand one more
concept. And that is the concept of packages. So let me just go back through my whiteboard
and that is what is a package now, right? So now think about it. It's the time of collaboration,
you're working with your team. Someone is working remotely. You're working from a remote location,
different location. So you collaborate using tools like Git, right? And so just imagine a scenario
where you name a class as task or Java, but your colleague also names a task or Java. And then
for such a trivial matter, you both are, yeah, are quarreling, right? That is your colleague says,
I named it task or Java first, but your argument is I named it first, right? So that is the first
use case of using packages or Java games, you now is the flexibility to have your own folders,
right? So they say, have your own classes in your own folders and they say or talk to your
colleague as have your classes in your own folders and these folders and in the Java programming
language are called packages. So in the code, these are packages at the back end, these are folders,
right? And obviously the ambiguity goes away, the conflict goes away, why? Because you would have
your own classes in your own folder, your colleague would have their own classes in their own
folder, for example, they'll just call their package as, let's say, my Inc and you would call
your own package as, for example, Gary, right? Now, Gary goes on and stores their classes in
their own package or folder, for example, task or Java, there is some Java and my Inc is working on
world or Java, he also has task and he also has do it or Java. But see, these two classes now,
tasks and tasks are named the same, but no more conflicts because they're represented now to the
outside world with their own folders or packages in Java, right? So the, the conflict goes away
and the other advantage of packages is code is organized better, why? Because my Inc has his own
files in his own package. Gargi has his her own files in her own package in her own folder,
right? And the third advantage is, let's say there's a problem with a file in Gargi's package,
the team leader, the project manager doesn't need to summon my Inc and other folks working in the
team. He just needs to summon Gargi and ask her, what is going on wrong in this some package,
in the some class belonging to the Gargi package, right? So that are some of the great advantages
which packages bring to the table. And why did I talk about packages is because they have
relations to how scope applies in Java, right? And packages now in the next video, we're first
going to know about how do we create our own packages in Java, how do we import them and what
relation do they have with scope?